[{"question":" Which types of indexes are available in CosmosDB?","options":[{"text":"range and spatial","correct":true},{"text":"secondary and primary key","correct":false},{"text":"secondary and spatial","correct":false},{"text":"range and primary key","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" You want to connect a DynamoDB stream to AWS Lambda function?","options":[{"text":"DynamoDB table","correct":false},{"text":"DynamoDB trigger","correct":true},{"text":"DynamoDB item","correct":false},{"text":"DynamoDB index","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" To index a field that holds an array value in MongoDB, which index type do you create?","options":[{"text":"partial","correct":false},{"text":"sparse","correct":false},{"text":"compound","correct":false},{"text":"multikey","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" You want to test HBASE on your laptop using the fewest number of steps. What do you do?","options":[{"text":"Set up Hadoop in pseudo-distributed mode.","correct":false},{"text":"Set up HBASE in local mode.","correct":false},{"text":"Set up HBASE in pseudo-distributed mode.","correct":true},{"text":"Set up Hadoop in local mode.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" You need to create a document database that supports database triggers. Which NoSQL database should you use?","options":[{"text":"DynamoDB","correct":true},{"text":"BigTable","correct":false},{"text":"Redis","correct":false},{"text":"MongoDB","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What is recommended size for Redis keys?","options":[{"text":"medium","correct":false},{"text":"short","correct":true},{"text":"single bit","correct":false},{"text":"long","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" You need to design security for DynamoDB to allow users read-only access to certain items and attributes in a table. What do you do?","options":[{"text":"Use lAM policy conditions","correct":false},{"text":"Use lAM roles","correct":false},{"text":"Use VPC endpoint","correct":false},{"text":"Use lAM policies","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What does redis use to sort the elements of a sorted set?","options":[{"text":"Scores.","correct":false},{"text":"Ids.","correct":false},{"text":"Values.","correct":false},{"text":"Keys.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":"You need to change the shard key of an existing MongoDB collection. What do you do?","options":[{"text":"Dump the collection data, drop the collection, create a new collection and shard key, import the data.","correct":false},{"text":"Add second shard key and drop the first shard key.","correct":false},{"text":"Dump the collection data, drop the collection, presplit the data, create a new collection and shard key, import the data.","correct":true},{"text":"Drop and recreate the shard key.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Polyglot storage means using multiple types of what in the same application?","options":[{"text":"Security systems.","correct":false},{"text":"Database systems.","correct":false},{"text":"Storage systems.","correct":false},{"text":"Query systems.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to implement the simplest possible scalable, in-memory cache for your AWS application. Which service do you select?","options":[{"text":"Elasticache using Memcached.","correct":false},{"text":"DynamoDB.","correct":false},{"text":"DynamoDB Accelerator (DAX).","correct":false},{"text":"Elasticache using Redis.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You are doing data modelling for Google BigTable. Which statement expresses if and when you should split entities across multiple rows?","options":[{"text":"Keep all information for an entity in a single row. Store related entities in adjacent rows.","correct":false},{"text":"Keep all information for an entity in a single row.","correct":false},{"text":"Split entities across multiple rows if the entity data is over thousands of MBs, or if it does not need atomic updates and reads.","correct":false},{"text":"Split entities across multiple rows if the entity data is over hundreds of MBs, or if it does not need atomic updates and reads.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which two characteristics define Amazon Quantum Ledger Database?","options":[{"text":"Key-value data model; transactionally consistent with ACID semantics.","correct":false},{"text":"Document data model; transactionally consistent with ACID semantics.","correct":true},{"text":"Key-value data model; transactions with tunable consistency.","correct":false},{"text":"Document data model; transactions with tunable consistency.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to design the primary key for DynamoDB based on three attributes. What do you do?","options":[{"text":"Designate all three fields as the primary key.","correct":false},{"text":"Concatenate all three fields into one new field, then designate that new field as the primary key.","correct":true},{"text":"Designate two fields of the three fields as the primary key.","correct":false},{"text":"Concatenate two fields into one new field, then designate that new field and the remaining field as the primary key.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to design the primary key for DynamoDB based on three attributes. What do you do?","options":[{"text":"Designate all three fields as the primary key.","correct":false},{"text":"Concatenate all three fields into one new field, then designate that new field as the primary key.","correct":true},{"text":"Designate two fields of the three fields as the primary key.","correct":false},{"text":"Concatenate two fields into one new field, then designate that new field and the remaining field as the primary key.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which of these data types should you avoid in designing a Google Bigtable row key?","options":[{"text":"multi-valued identifiers","correct":false},{"text":"string identifiers","correct":false},{"text":"timesstamps","correct":false},{"text":"frequently updated identifiers","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Your startup is building a prototype that has an evolving schema. Your data will be eventually consistent. Your application is hosted in AWS. Which databse do you choose?","options":[{"text":"Neptune","correct":false},{"text":"DocumentDB","correct":false},{"text":"DynamoDB","correct":true},{"text":"Amazon Aurora","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to create a scalable databse that allows you to share documents across authorized mobile clients in real time. What Google NoSQL database should you use?","options":[{"text":"Memorystore","correct":false},{"text":"Datastore","correct":false},{"text":"Firebase","correct":true},{"text":"Bigtable","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to test HBase on your laptop using the fewest number of steps. What do you do?","options":[{"text":"Set up HBase in local mode.","correct":false},{"text":"Set up Hadoop in pseudo-distributed mode.","correct":false},{"text":"Set up HBase in pseudo-distributed mode.","correct":false},{"text":"Set up Hadoop in local mode.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to design security for DynamoDB to allow users read-obly access to certain items and attriutes in a table. What do you do?","options":[{"text":"Use IAM roles.","correct":false},{"text":"Use IAM plicy conditions.","correct":true},{"text":"Use a VPC endpoint.","correct":false},{"text":"Use IAM plicies.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to design a primary key for DynamoDb based on three attributes. What do you do?","options":[{"text":"Concatenate all three fields into into one new field, than disignate that new field as the primary key.","correct":false},{"text":"Concatenate two fileds into one new field, than disignate that new field and the remaining field as the primary key.","correct":false},{"text":"Designate all three fields as the primary key.","correct":true},{"text":"Designate two filds of the three fields as the primary key.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What does Redis use to sort the elements of a sorted set?","options":[{"text":"keys","correct":false},{"text":"values","correct":false},{"text":"scroes","correct":true},{"text":"ids","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to create a document database that supports database triggers. Which NoSQL database should you use?","options":[{"text":"DynamoDb","correct":true},{"text":"Redis","correct":false},{"text":"MongoDB","correct":false},{"text":"Bigtable","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which statement is prefered Cypher code for Neo4j?","options":[{"text":"MATCH (:Person)-->(:Card)-->(:Company) RETURN count(vehicle)","correct":false},{"text":"Match (:Person)-->(:Car):(vehicle:Car)-->(:Company) RETURN count(vehicle)","correct":false},{"text":"MATCH (:Person)-->(vehicle:Car)-->(:Company) RETURN count(vehicle)","correct":true},{"text":"MATCH (:Person)-->(:Card), (vehicle:Car)-->(:Company) RETURN count(vehicle)","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need multi-item ACID transactions with snapshot isolation within a partition for your cloud-based application. Which NoSQL databse do you choose?","options":[{"text":"Bigtable","correct":false},{"text":"GraphDB","correct":false},{"text":"DynamoDB","correct":false},{"text":"Cosmos DB","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to control your application's batch updates destination for your Bigtable multinode cluster. Which action do you take?","options":[{"text":"Create a custom app profile to route batch updates.","correct":false},{"text":"Create a custom app profile to route the batch update from that client.","correct":false},{"text":"Update the default app profile to route the natch update from that client.","correct":true},{"text":"Use the default app profile to route batch updates.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Polyglot storage mean using multiple types of what in the same application?","options":[{"text":"security systems","correct":false},{"text":"databse systems","correct":false},{"text":"query systems","correct":false},{"text":"storage systems","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Your query to verify that your Redis key is configured to support expiring user information on a defined interval returns -2, What does this value indicate?","options":[{"text":"The queried key value expired in the last two secodns.","correct":false},{"text":"The queried key value exists, but has no associated expire value.","correct":false},{"text":"The queried key value does not exist.","correct":true},{"text":"There are two expired keys with this value.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You are designing a MongoDB schema to support queries that will include lookups. What should you do?","options":[{"text":"Create an index on the key value used as the primary key.","correct":false},{"text":"Create an index on the key value used as the foreign key.","correct":false},{"text":"Create a multicolumn index on the key value used as the foreign key and the most unique column in the document.","correct":true},{"text":"Create a multicolumn index on the key value used as the primary and also the forign key.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the aggregation operator for a join concept in MongoDB?","options":[{"text":"\\$group","correct":false},{"text":"\\$match","correct":false},{"text":"\\$lookup","correct":true},{"text":"\\$project","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". For your mobile application, you need to select a Google cloud databse that can support compound, filtered document queries. Which do you choose?","options":[{"text":"Cloud SQL","correct":false},{"text":"Cloud Spanner","correct":false},{"text":"Cloud Firestore","correct":true},{"text":"Cloud Firebase","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". To bulk load data into Amazon Neputn, what do you do?","options":[{"text":"Upload data to S3 VPC endpoint, Use the Neptun loader to load from s3 into your Neptune instance","correct":true},{"text":"Ad data to a Kinesis stream, and use the Neptune loade to load from S# into your Neptun instance.","correct":false},{"text":"Add data to a Kisnesis stream, and create a Kinesis stream VPC endpoint. Use the Nepune loader to load from S3into your Neptune instance.","correct":false},{"text":"Upload data to S Use the neptune loader to load from S3 into your Neptune instance.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to create a pub/sub server. Which databse do you use?","options":[{"text":"Neo4j","correct":false},{"text":"Cassandra","correct":false},{"text":"Redis","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":"S#### QL","options":[],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to connect a DynamoDb stream to an AWS lamdba function. Which one of these object do you create.","options":[{"text":"DynamoDb table","correct":false},{"text":"DynamoDB trigger","correct":true},{"text":"DynamoDB item","correct":false},{"text":"DYnamoDB index","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which two types of indexes are available in Cosmos DB?","options":[{"text":"secondery and primary key","correct":true},{"text":"secondary and spatial","correct":false},{"text":"range and spatial","correct":false},{"text":"range and primary key","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". SQL databses and NoSQL are which types of scalable?","options":[{"text":"horizontally, infinitely","correct":false},{"text":"vertically, horizontally","correct":true},{"text":"vertically, infinitely","correct":false},{"text":"horizonally, vertically","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to create a scalable database that allows you to query data nodes and edges efficiently. What do you use?","options":[{"text":"a relational databse","correct":false},{"text":"a columnstore databse","correct":false},{"text":"a document databse","correct":false},{"text":"a graph database","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You are developing a model for a graph databse. Your data will be moved from a relatinal databse into Neo4j. Which of these transformations apply?","options":[{"text":"Rows become labes: bales become nodes.","correct":false},{"text":"Tables become labels: rows become nodes.","correct":false},{"text":"Tables become collections: rows become items.","correct":false},{"text":"Rows become collections: tables become items.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". To index a field that holds an array value in MongoDB, which index type do you create?","options":[{"text":"sparse","correct":false},{"text":"compound","correct":false},{"text":"partial","correct":false},{"text":"multikey","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to execute a command for MongoDB that does NOT load values from the `.mongorc.js` file. What do you do ?","options":[{"text":"Delete the .monorc.js file and restart mongo shell.","correct":false},{"text":"Use the mongo shell to create a command with --norc option","correct":false},{"text":"Rem all lines in the .mongorc.js file ad restart mongo shell.","correct":false},{"text":"Use the mongo shell to create a command with --nodedefault option.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the recommended size for Redis keys?","options":[{"text":"long","correct":false},{"text":"short","correct":false},{"text":"medium","correct":false},{"text":"a single bit","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to store an unordered collection of name-value pairs with differing data types in DynamoDB. Which data type should you choose?","options":[{"text":"map","correct":true},{"text":"set","correct":false},{"text":"list","correct":false},{"text":"stack","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which statement retrieves an item from the MusicCollection table in DynamoDB?","options":[{"text":"aws dynamodb query --table-name MusicCollection --key file://key.json","correct":false},{"text":"aws dynamodb get-item --table-name MusicCollection --key file://key.json","correct":true},{"text":"aws dynamodb select --table-name MusicCollection --key file://key.json","correct":false},{"text":"aws dynamodb put-item --table-name MusicCollection --key file://key.json","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Database availability is measured by which metric?","options":[{"text":"the amount of service calls","correct":false},{"text":"the number of minutes","correct":false},{"text":"the amount of service costs","correct":false},{"text":"the number of nines","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to encrypt data at rest in DynamoDB. Which action do you take?","options":[{"text":"You assign a default AWS encryption key to your table to encrypt data.","correct":false},{"text":"You create an AWS encryption key and assign it to your table to encrypt data.","correct":false},{"text":"None. Data is encrypted by default.","correct":true},{"text":"You create an AWS encryption key and assign it to your database to encrypt data.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You need to generate a unique, sequential identifier for each value stored in a Redis cluster. What do you do?","options":[{"text":"Implement a SortedSet object to generate a value.","correct":false},{"text":"Use the GUID keyword to generate a value.","correct":false},{"text":"Implement a List object to generate a value.","correct":false},{"text":"Use the INCR keyword to generate a value","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You want to return a list of all elements in two Redis sets. Which keyword do you use?","options":[{"text":"smembers","correct":true},{"text":"returnall","correct":false},{"text":"sunion","correct":false},{"text":"sismember","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which method shows you whether MongoDB uses any indexes when running a query, and how the indexes are used?","options":[{"text":"detailQueryExecution()","correct":false},{"text":"showPlan()","correct":false},{"text":"explain()","correct":true},{"text":"describe()","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which statement accurately describes global secondary indexes in DynamoDB?","options":[{"text":"The global secondary indexes in DynamoDB are consistent, and are not guaranteed to return correct results.","correct":false},{"text":"The global secondary indexes in DynamoDB are transactionally consistent, and are guaranteed to return correct results.","correct":false},{"text":"The global secondary indexes in DynamoDB are partially consistent, and are not guaranteed to return correct results.","correct":false},{"text":"The global secondary indexes in DynamoDB are eventually consistent, and are not guaranteed to return correct results.","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which command do you use to add a value to a Redis stream named mystream?","options":[{"text":"ADD mystream \\* sensor-id 1234 temperature 19.8 1518951480106-1","correct":false},{"text":"UPDATE mystream \\* sensor-id 1234 temperature 19.8 1518951480106-3","correct":false},{"text":"XADD mystream \\* sensor-id 1234 temperature 9.8 1518951480106-0","correct":true},{"text":"INSERT mystream \\* sensor-d 1234 temperature 19.8 15181480106-2","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which code example completes this statement and creates an index for a MongoDB object named restaurants, sorted ascending by the field name?","options":[{"text":"`const results = yield db.table('restaurants').createIndex({\"name\": 1}, null); return results;`","correct":false},{"text":"`const results = yield db.collection('restaurants').createIndex({\"name\": 0}, null); return results;`","correct":false},{"text":"`const results = yield db.collection('restaurants').createIndex({\"name\": 1}, null); return results;`","correct":true},{"text":"`const results = yield db.table('restaurants').createIndex({\"name\": 0}, null); return results;`","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nvar indexCollection = function(db) {return co(function*() {...});};\n```"},{"question":". Which Cypher code executes the multiquery block?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"A ledger database","correct":true},{"text":"A graph database","correct":false},{"text":"A key-value database","correct":false},{"text":"A columnstore database","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nMATCH (c:Company {name: 'Neo4j'}) RETURN c;MATCH (p:Person) WHERE p.name = 'Jennifer' RETURN p;\nMATCH (t:Technology)-[:LIKES]-(a:Person {name: 'Jennifer'}) RETURN t.type;\n```"}]